Summary

Passionate full-stack developer, experienced with React/NextJs (TypeScript) and NodeJs (TypeScript/JavaScript), with past experience with Spring (Java), currently working as a consultant developer. Keep a medium blog on React and maths, love all things tech related.

Skills

Technical: JavaScript, TypeScript, React, React Native, NodeJs, NextJs, Java, Python, Spring, Express, Selenium,

JUnit, jest, PostgreSQL, SQLite, MDB, Android, Figma, Docker, Git, Maven, Gradle, Jira

Work Experience

Capgemini Invent, London (Remote): Software Developer Consultant

Oct 2022 - Present

Building a healthcare solution that automates SR1 form submission for a greenfield project.

- Took on the leading role for the front-end development in creating a server-side rendered app in Node with TypeScript.
- Collaborated with User Research and Design to optimize user journey and accelerated prototype completion.
- Empowered more junior colleagues to continuously improve with pair programming sessions and in-depth code reviews.
- Ensured over 99% test coverage with Mocha test framework

Helped develop a SaaS PoC for monitoring company CO2 emissions for investors.

- Contributed to front-end development of a web-app using React with TypeScript
- Ensured over 90% test coverage with Jest

1Spatial, Cambridge: Full-stack software developer

Sep 2021 - Oct 2022

Help develop a user-friendly web application for interacting with the company's business rules engine.

- Building secure RESTful API endpoints using Spring (Java) which supports authentication using SAML and OAuth2.
- Developing UI in React (TypeScript) for a web SaaS with users in 6 different industries spanning 4 countries.
- Asserting a minimum of 80% test coverage using JUnit and Selenium testing frameworks.
- Maintaining a PostgreSQL database.

Impression Agency, Remote: Software developer

May 2021 - Jul 2021

Contracted to develop a tool for for automating competitor analysis.

- Automated YouTuber sponsor competitor analysis, speeding up to be less than 1 minute.
- Removed the need to do the task by hand, skyrocketing productivity.

Education

2017 - 2021	MEng Computer Science, Univeristy of Southampton 2:1
2015 - 2017	A Levels, Northgate Sixth Form A* A* A* B B
2011 - 2015	GCSEs, Northgate High School 10 GCSEs A* - C





